Speaker 1: British and American English – the same, but different
British and American people speak the same language – English – but with some small differences.
1 Vocabulary
Some words are different in American English, for example, they say zip code not postcode,
vacation not holiday, and elevator not lift.
Some words have different meanings, for example, in British English,
a purse is a wallet for women, for money and bank cards. In American English, a purse is a bag.
Speaker 2: 2 Spelling
Colour, favour, and other words that end in -our in British English end in -or in American English.
Centre, theatre, and other words that end in -tre in British English end in -ter in American English.
Speaker 1: 3 Grammar
There are some small differences, especially prepositions.
For example, Americans say See you Friday, but British people say See you on Friday.
Speaker 2: 4 Pronunciation
This is the really important difference between American and British English.
American accents and British accents are very different.
When Americans start speaking, British people know they are American, and vice versa.